{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Small charged molecules, often biogenic amines function as", "opta": "hormones", "optb": "neurotransmitters", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "SH2 domains specifically bind to", "opta": "phosphorylated serine residues", "optb": "phosphorylated tyrosine residues", "optc": "GDP", "optd": "Ca2+", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In paracrine signaling, the signaling molecules affects only", "opta": "target cells close to the cell from which it was secreted", "optb": "target cells distant from its site of synthesis in cells of an endocrine organ", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Simple nerve reflexes use signaling molecules called", "opta": "neurotransmitters", "optb": "nitric oxides", "optc": "G proteins", "optd": "proteases", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a type of signaling molecule?", "opta": "Testosterone", "optb": "Insulin", "optc": "Thyroxin", "optd": "Adenylate cyclase", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Self-phosphorylation is an excellent mechanism for triggering specific catalytic function of the proteins involved in signal cascades because it", "opta": "changes the shape and thus the enzymatic activity of the proteins involved", "optb": "makes the receptor more likely to capture the signaling, molecule", "optc": "allows hydrophilic signaling molecules to cross the plasma membrane", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statements about G proteins is false?", "opta": "They are involved in signal cascades", "optb": "They bind to and are regulated by guanine nucleotides", "optc": "They become activated when bound to GDP", "optd": "They must be active before the cell can make needed cAMP", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When a __________ reaches its __________ , there is a specific means of receiving it and acting on the message. This task is the responsibility of specialized proteins called __________ .", "opta": "signaling molecule; receptor; G proteins", "optb": "signaling molecule; target cell; G proteins", "optc": "signaling molecule; target cell; receptors", "optd": "kinase; receptor; proteases", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Why is it that inhaling nitric oxide reduces blood pressure only in the lung tissue and not elsewhere in the body*?", "opta": "Because other body tissues use a different signaling molecule", "optb": "Because nitric oxide cannot cross cell membranes and enter the blood", "optc": "Because nitric oxide breaks down quickly and thus cannot travel far", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following comes under the category of cell surface receptor?", "opta": "Enzyme linked receptors", "optb": "Ion-channel linked receptors", "optc": "G protein linked receptors", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is true about a hydrophilic signaling molecule?", "opta": "Its receptor is located in the cytosol of the target cell", "optb": "It might trigger a signal cascade that causes some effect in a cell", "optc": "Since it can enter the cell, it directly affects some specific cell process", "optd": "It is a steroid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "cAMP and cGMP are derived from", "opta": "ATP and GTP by the actions of adenylate cyclase and guanylate cyclase respectively", "optb": "GTP and ATP by the actions of adenylate cyclase and guanylate cyclase respectively", "optc": "ATP and GTP by the actions of guanylate cyclase and adenylate cyclase respectively", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Nitroglycerin has long been administered to human patients suffering from chronic chest pain (angina). This medication works because it", "opta": "mimics the action of signal receptors", "optb": "is broken down into hormones that affect the heart", "optc": "interferes with chemical cascades that trigger contraction of heart muscle", "optd": "breaks down into nitric oxide, which increases blood flow to the heart", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a disease of the blood vessels caused the endothelial cells of the vessel to die, what effect would that have on the cellular activities associated with vasodilation?", "opta": "Nitric oxide would no longer be produced", "optb": "Smooth muscle cells could not be made to relax", "optc": "It would be more difficult to increase blood flow and reduce blood pressure", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In terms of cell communication, what do bacterial pathogens such as cholera and anthrax have in common?", "opta": "They destroy the receptors for key signaling molecules", "optb": "They prevent the production of key signaling molecules", "optc": "They alter the chemical structure of key signaling molecules", "optd": "They block the normal functioning of signal transduction mechanisms", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the name of the protein signaling molecule that alters glucose uptake, and where would its receptors be located?", "opta": "Insulin; many different cell types that use glucose for fuel", "optb": "Insulin; beta cells of the pancreas", "optc": "PDGF; the blood", "optd": "NGF; the nerves involved in simple reflexes", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In the signal transduction mechanism known as protein phosphorylation", "opta": "the signaling molecule binds to a surface receptor", "optb": "receptor kinases play a key role in triggering the signal cascade", "optc": "phosphorylated proteins act with enzymes to trigger the signal cascade", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Cell signaling can be classified into", "opta": "three distinct types based on the distance over which the signaling molecules act", "optb": "two distinct types based on the distance over which the signaling molecules act", "optc": "three distinct types based on the signaling molecules", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is correct?", "opta": "Cell communicate with one another in multicellular organisms using extracellular signaling molecules or hormones", "optb": "Cell communicate with one another in unicellular organisms using extracellular signaling antigen and antibody", "optc": "Cell communicate with one another in multicellular organisms using intracellular signaling molecules only", "optd": "Cell communicate with one another in unicellular organisms using intracellular signaling antigen and antibody", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In vasodilation, proper nerve signals sent to blood vessels cause", "opta": "the release of nitric oxide from endothelial cells", "optb": "relaxation of smooth muscle cells", "optc": "reduced blood pressure", "optd": "All of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A cell is known to respond to a particular signaling molecule. Which of the following must be true of this cell?", "opta": "It is in the heart muscle", "optb": "It is also the site of production for the signaling molecule", "optc": "It contains the receptor for the signaling molecule", "optd": "It is incapable of signal transduction", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The enzyme that catalyzes the splitting of PIP2 into two molecules of inositol triphosphate (IP3) and diacylglycerol in cell signaling, is", "opta": "phosphokinase C", "optb": "phospholipase C", "optc": "phosphodiesterase C", "optd": "lipokinase", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binding of ligands to many G-proteins linked receptors leads to shortlived", "opta": "increase in the concentration of certain intracellular signaling molecules called second messenger", "optb": "decrease in the concentration of certain intracellular signaling molecules called second messenger", "optc": "increase in the concentration of certain extracellular signaling molecules called first messenger", "optd": "decrease in the concentration of certain extracellular signaling molecules called first messenger", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following processes involve the combining of a message from one signaling molecule with that of another to either enhance or inhibit a cellular effect?", "opta": "Signal transduction", "optb": "Signal reception", "optc": "Signal integration", "optd": "Signal amplification", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A signal cascade induced by adrenaline or thyroxine", "opta": "must begin with receipt of the signal molecule by a surface receptor", "optb": "involves the activation of a G protein", "optc": "results in the activation of a sequence of enzymes needed for the cell effect", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a second messenger?", "opta": "lnositol 1,4,5-triphosphate", "optb": "Diacyl glycerol", "optc": "Phospholipase C", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following statement is incorrect?", "opta": "The principal lipophilic hormones that binds to receptors located in the plasma membranes are prostaglandins", "optb": "Prostaglandins are synthesized from arachidonic acid", "optc": "Prostaglandins act as paracrine signaling molecules", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Two key organizing principles for large multicellular organisms are", "opta": "prokaryotic cell structure and cell specialization", "optb": "cell specialization and communication between cells", "optc": "communication between cells and simple nerve reflexes", "optd": "simple nerve reflexes and cell specialization", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a hormone whose action requires a cell surface receptor?", "opta": "Nitric oxide", "optb": "Progesterone", "optc": "Adrenaline", "optd": "Growth factors", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The hormone or ligand can be considered as", "opta": "first messenger", "optb": "second messenger", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The major second messengers are", "opta": "cAMP", "optb": "cGMP", "optc": "DAG", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The signaling molecules called steroid hormones", "opta": "are made in one location of the body but have their effects some distance away", "optb": "are hydrophilic and so cannot penetrate the plasma membrane", "optc": "bind to cell surface receptors to trigger chemical cascades", "optd": "never enter the blood of humans", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}